Adam McKenna

Full Stack Developer

I builld useful products that people actually enjoy using.

I'm a full stack developer focused on **React**, **TypeScript**, and **Node.js** — comfortable across the stack, and committed to writing **clean code** and creating **rich**, **accessible user experiences**.

EXPERIENCE

Frontend Developer

Track24

Dec 2024 - Present - London, UK (Remote)

Re-developed *AtlasNXT* user interface, increasing usability in high-risk environments for users across the *BBC*, *United Nations* and UK Gov't *FCDO*.

Tech: Elixir (Phoenix), React.js, TypeScript, TailwindCSS, Mapbox.js

Full Stack Developer

Binary Vision

Aug 2022 - Mar 2023 - London, UK

Developed *Oi View*, a data visualisation platform for *Oxford Instruments* that increased direct client interaction by over 50%.

Tech: React (Next.js), TypeScript, Node.js, react-spring

Senior Frontend Developer

DWP Digital (UK Gov't)

Apr 2021 - Oct 2021 - Sheffield/Manchester, UK

Shipped auth and admin tools that improved efficiency for internal teams across DWP, and for improved auth for thousands of DWP claimants.

Tech: React, Node.js, GOV.UK Design System, ForgeRock

Full Stack Developer

Money Advice Trust

Jan 2020 - Apr 2021 - Birmingham, UK

Led the rebuild/relaunch of three web apps for a UK debt-support charity, significantly improving performance, accessibility and audience reach.

Tech: React (Gatsby.js, Next.js), Django (Python), Stencil.js

Frontend Developer

Namics GmbH

Sep 2018 - Nov 2019 - Frankfurt am Main, Germany

Delivered *Analytics Unlocked*, a marketing analytics dashboard for *Siemens*, enabling teams to analyse and optimise marketing worldwide.

Tech: React, TypeScript, Material UI, react-spring

EDUCATION

BSc Computer Science

University of Sunderland

2014 - 2018 (with 1 year industrial placement at Gospelware)



adam-mckenna@outlook.com +44 7404 895 383 Newcastle upon Tyne, UK

Programming Languages

JavaScript / TypeScript

PHP

Elixir

HTML

CSS / SASS

Core Technologies

Frontend: React, Vue, Angular **Backend:** Node.js (Express, Nest.js), Laravel, Phoenix (Elixir)

Tooling: Vite, Jest (testing)

DevOps: AWS

Other: TailwindCSS, A11y

Other Skills

Leadership

Pragmatism

Independence

UX/UI + service design

Languages

English (native)

German (conversational)

Links

adammckenna.online
linkedin.com/in/adam-mckenna
github.com/adam-mckenna
dev.to/adammckenna